<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://ldstephens.net/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://ldstephens.net/" />
  <updated>2025-04-16T15:33:31Z</updated>
  <id>https://ldstephens.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Loren Stephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Post Number 500</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/post-number-500/" />
    <updated>2025-04-16T15:33:31Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/post-number-500/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I didn’t start this blog in 2016 with any big plan. I just wanted a place to share how I use my tech: apps, workflows, devices, the setups that make things click for me. Write a post, hit publish, move on to the next thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m figuring things out as I go. Sometimes I’m just documenting what works or doesn’t work. Either way, the goal’s always been the same: share what I’ve learned in case it helps someone else or future me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read any of these 500 posts, thanks. I’m glad you’re here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post - Just Put It On Your Blog</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-just-put-it-on-your-blog/" />
    <updated>2025-04-16T09:28:50Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-just-put-it-on-your-blog/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got something to say, something to share, something that others might be interested in—why not &lt;strong&gt;just put it on your blog&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shellsharks.com/just-put-it-on-your-blog&quot;&gt;Michael Sass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My thoughts on analytics and this site</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/my-thoughts-on-analytics-and-this-site/" />
    <updated>2025-04-15T12:34:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/my-thoughts-on-analytics-and-this-site/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&#39;ve been thinking about whether to add analytics to this site. A lot of personal sites use them, and that&#39;s totally fine. Back when this site was on WordPress, it had analytics too. But when I moved to 11ty and Netlify, I chose not to add them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the migration, everything I write here has been free from the influence of analytics. No pressure to write what performs. I&#39;m just writing on my own terms, at my own pace. This site is simple and personal and I want to keep it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Drafts subscription</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/drafts-subscription/" />
    <updated>2025-04-14T14:07:39Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/drafts-subscription/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been whittling down my subscription apps, and the last one on the list was &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;. I let it expire on April 7th, thinking I could get by with the free version. I could, but decided I didn&#39;t want to. So I resubscribed yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link post - If your content is only on social media, I&#39;m not going to see it</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-if-your-content-is-only-on-social-media-im-not-going-to-see-it/" />
    <updated>2025-04-12T09:29:19Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-if-your-content-is-only-on-social-media-im-not-going-to-see-it/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&#39;ve elected to eschew all of these platforms, I find myself in a position in which discovery can (and often is) problematic and curation is of paramount importance. It&#39;s a slow moving process of following blogs, following blogs and authors they link to and doing the same with news services. It&#39;s an approach to the internet that&#39;s both slower and freer. I can finish scrolling what I follow because none of it&#39;s designed to keep me engaged in perpetuity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coryd.dev/posts/2025/if-your-content-is-only-on-social-media-im-not-going-to-see-it/&quot;&gt;Cory Dransfeldt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well put, Cory. It takes time and effort to build a good set of personal blogs to follow, ones you actually enjoy reading. Every day, as I go through my reading list, I check out any blogs people link to. That&#39;s exactly how I found Cory&#39;s blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I almost fell for it</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/i-almost-fell-for-it/" />
    <updated>2025-04-08T14:38:20Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/i-almost-fell-for-it/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I almost fell for a $200 discount on the base model M4 MacBook Pro. I had convinced myself that I should get a new MacBook to replace my M1 in order to avoid a potential price increase due to the fucking tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across the offer from Amazon on &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2025/04/07/m4-macbook-pro-reasons-worth-upgrading-now/&quot;&gt;9to5&lt;/a&gt;. Since I’m not a fan of buying hardware from Amazon, I reached out to Best Buy, and they graciously matched the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sleeping on it overnight, I convinced myself to hold tight. Besides, I should be getting the base model Air with a 512 SSD, not the base model Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iA Writer and Grammarly</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/ia-writer-and-grammarly/" />
    <updated>2025-04-07T14:59:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/ia-writer-and-grammarly/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like to run my blog posts through Grammarly before publishing to catch spelling and grammar mistakes. However, one thing that bugs me about iA Writer is that it doesn’t work well with Grammarly. It kind of works, but not really. iA Writer won’t accept rephrase suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’d like to use iA Writer for blog posts, notes, and journaling, I contacted their support team to see if there’s a fix. Here’s what they said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our apps, iA Writer and iA Presenter, do not support Grammarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grammarly and iA Writer handle user data differently. While we don’t collect any of your information, Grammarly does. Because of this data privacy conflict, we’ve decided not to integrate the Grammarly API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the answer I was hoping for. I’ll figure out a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post - Our Tools Shape Us</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-our-tools-shape-us/" />
    <updated>2025-04-07T10:47:43Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-our-tools-shape-us/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nice-marmot.net/Archives/2025/March_2025.html#note_2879&quot;&gt;Dave Rogers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Writing is thinking&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;quot;[…] It&#39;s the &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; where the creative act occurs, the &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt;.[…] If you want to get the most from your practice, first, &lt;em&gt;have a practice&lt;/em&gt;. Then, stick with one tool. Find one that that appeals to you, doesn&#39;t get in your way, and &lt;em&gt;use it&lt;/em&gt;.[…] If you want something that&#39;s &lt;em&gt;yours&lt;/em&gt;, that&#39;s &lt;em&gt;meaningful to you&lt;/em&gt;, then build a relationship with a tool that serves you, and remain faithful to it. If you outgrow it someday, you&#39;ll know. And you&#39;ll know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some good advice on the tools that we use.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remind Me Faster</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/remind-me-faster/" />
    <updated>2025-04-06T15:55:38Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/remind-me-faster/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.net/blog/reminders-menubar/&quot;&gt;messing around&lt;/a&gt; with Apple’s Reminders app. I’m still using Things, but I found a handy iOS app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/remind-me-faster/id985555908&quot;&gt;Remind Me Faster&lt;/a&gt; that makes adding tasks to Reminders super quick. Why does that matter if I’m using Things? Because Things 3 can import tasks from the Reminders Inbox list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use the iOS share sheet to send something to Things, you can’t set a due date or time. But with Remind Me Faster, you can. It lets you create a reminder with a due date and time in the Reminders Inbox, ready for Things to import. Whether you’re using Reminders or Things I think you’ll like this little app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Still waffling on Feedbin</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/still-waffling-on-feedbin/" />
    <updated>2025-04-05T15:21:05Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/still-waffling-on-feedbin/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was flipping back and forth between Feedbin and iCloud sync in Reeder, still debating whether I could drop my Feedbin subscription, even though I had already &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-on-ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/&quot;&gt;decided to keep it&lt;/a&gt;. In the middle of all that, I noticed the “On My iPhone” feed option. I hadn’t really thought about using that before (oops). So I uploaded all my feeds to it and have been using it since. And you know what? It works great. It’s not quite as fast as Feedbin, but it’s fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big plus is privacy, since everything’s stored on my iPhone, no service is tracking what I follow or read. That might not work for folks who need their feeds to sync across devices, but I do all my RSS reading on my iPhone, so it’s a perfect fit for me. This means I can finally ditch my Feedbin subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>