<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://ldstephens.net/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://ldstephens.net/" />
  <updated>2025-04-07T14:59:53Z</updated>
  <id>https://ldstephens.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Loren Stephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>iA Writer and Grammarly</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/ia-writer-and-grammarly/" />
    <updated>2025-04-07T14:59:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/ia-writer-and-grammarly/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like to run my blog posts through Grammarly before publishing to catch spelling and grammar mistakes. However, one thing that bugs me about iA Writer is that it doesn’t work well with Grammarly. It kind of works, but not really. iA Writer won’t accept rephrase suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’d like to use iA Writer for blog posts, notes, and journaling, I contacted their support team to see if there’s a fix. Here’s what they said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our apps, iA Writer and iA Presenter, do not support Grammarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grammarly and iA Writer handle user data differently. While we don’t collect any of your information, Grammarly does. Because of this data privacy conflict, we’ve decided not to integrate the Grammarly API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the answer I was hoping for. I’ll figure out a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post - Our Tools Shape Us</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-our-tools-shape-us/" />
    <updated>2025-04-07T10:47:43Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-our-tools-shape-us/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nice-marmot.net/Archives/2025/March_2025.html#note_2879&quot;&gt;Dave Rogers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Writing is thinking&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;quot;[…] It&#39;s the &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; where the creative act occurs, the &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt;.[…] If you want to get the most from your practice, first, &lt;em&gt;have a practice&lt;/em&gt;. Then, stick with one tool. Find one that that appeals to you, doesn&#39;t get in your way, and &lt;em&gt;use it&lt;/em&gt;.[…] If you want something that&#39;s &lt;em&gt;yours&lt;/em&gt;, that&#39;s &lt;em&gt;meaningful to you&lt;/em&gt;, then build a relationship with a tool that serves you, and remain faithful to it. If you outgrow it someday, you&#39;ll know. And you&#39;ll know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some good advice on the tools that we use.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remind Me Faster</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/remind-me-faster/" />
    <updated>2025-04-06T15:55:38Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/remind-me-faster/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.net/blog/reminders-menubar/&quot;&gt;messing around&lt;/a&gt; with Apple’s Reminders app. I’m still using Things, but I found a handy iOS app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/remind-me-faster/id985555908&quot;&gt;Remind Me Faster&lt;/a&gt; that makes adding tasks to Reminders super quick. Why does that matter if I’m using Things? Because Things 3 can import tasks from the Reminders Inbox list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use the iOS share sheet to send something to Things, you can’t set a due date or time. But with Remind Me Faster, you can. It lets you create a reminder with a due date and time in the Reminders Inbox, ready for Things to import. Whether you’re using Reminders or Things I think you’ll like this little app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Still waffling on Feedbin</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/still-waffling-on-feedbin/" />
    <updated>2025-04-05T15:21:05Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/still-waffling-on-feedbin/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was flipping back and forth between Feedbin and iCloud sync in Reeder, still debating whether I could drop my Feedbin subscription, even though I had already &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-on-ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/&quot;&gt;decided to keep it&lt;/a&gt;. In the middle of all that, I noticed the “On My iPhone” feed option. I hadn’t really thought about using that before (oops). So I uploaded all my feeds to it and have been using it since. And you know what? It works great. It’s not quite as fast as Feedbin, but it’s fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big plus is privacy, since everything’s stored on my iPhone, no service is tracking what I follow or read. That might not work for folks who need their feeds to sync across devices, but I do all my RSS reading on my iPhone, so it’s a perfect fit for me. This means I can finally ditch my Feedbin subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update - on ditching my Feedbin subscription</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-on-ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/" />
    <updated>2025-04-02T15:39:50Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-on-ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.net/blog/ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; ditching my Feedbin subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Feedbin renewal is coming up in a couple of months, and I’ve made up my mind I’m not renewing. So today, I updated my feeds in NetNewsWire and started using it full-time. That way, by the time my Feedbin subscription expires, I’ll be comfortable with the switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iCloud sync is a total pain in the ass. It’s especially bad in Reeder Classic. NetNewsWire handles it a bit better, but I just can’t keep using it. It’s a fantastic free app, and I’d definitely recommend it to others, but it’s not for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided to change my mind, I’ll keep my Feedbin subscription and stick with Reeder.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reminders MenuBar</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/reminders-menubar/" />
    <updated>2025-04-01T14:46:51Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/reminders-menubar/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I’ve been bouncing between Things 3 and GoodTask with Reminders as the back-end for a few years. Lately, I&#39;ve been using Things. But yesterday, I was bored (that happens when you&#39;re retired), so I decided to brush off GoodTask and start using it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem? I have GoodTask on my iPhone and iPad, but not on my MacBook. I&#39;ve tried the Mac trial, but I don&#39;t like it. Plus, it’s a $40 purchase that I don&#39;t want to make. I dislike the Reminders app even more. So I needed a way to access Reminders on my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, I can view and add Reminders using Raycast plugins, so I don&#39;t need a dedicated app on my MacBook. But during this process, I stumbled on a new menubar utility that&#39;s pretty cool: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DamascenoRafael/reminders-menubar&quot;&gt;Reminders MenuBar&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s easy to access with a keyboard shortcut, making it super convenient. If you use Reminders, you might want to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still haven’t decided which way I’m going to go. For now, I running both options side by side.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The power of _redirects</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/the-power-of-redirects/" />
    <updated>2025-03-30T15:50:57Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/the-power-of-redirects/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, when I migrated ldstephens from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/migrate/wordpress/&quot;&gt;WordPress to Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;, I had a three goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure old links redirected to the new structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure the old RSS feed redirected to the new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep RSS subscribers from ldstephens.me connected, so they wouldn&#39;t have to change anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Netlify redirects, I made all of this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redirecting Old URLs to New URLs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/2016/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2017/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2018/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2019/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2020/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2021/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2022/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2023/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
/2024/*/:slug/ /blog/:slug/ 301!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirects /YYYY/MM/DD/slug/ to /blog/slug/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeps the original post slug intact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses a 301 permanent redirect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redirecting the Old RSS Feed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/feed      https://ldstephens.net/feed/feed.xml    301
/feed.xml  https://ldstephens.net/feed/feed.xml    301
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, anyone subscribed to the old feed gets the new one automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping ldstephens.me RSS Subscribers Connected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On ldstephens.me, I updated the _redirects file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/feed      https://ldstephens.net/feed  200!
/feed.xml  https://ldstephens.net/feed.xml  200!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of redirecting, this proxies requests to the new feed. The 200! ensures the feed loads from ldstephens.net instead of bouncing users around. The catch, both sites need to be on Netlify for this to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m new to this kind of thing, so being able to set up redirects felt like fucking magic. You just can&#39;t do this if your site is locked into a hosted platform. This is why owning your blog matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update regarding ldstephens - March 27, 2025</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-regarding-ldstephens-march-27-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-03-27T15:55:06Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-regarding-ldstephens-march-27-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, you may have noticed a flurry of activity here at ldstephens in the last few days. As long-time followers know, this site started on WordPress.com in 2016. Around the time WordPress made changes to the editor forcing users to use the new block editor that I fucking hated I basically stopped posting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past several months, I’ve been experimenting with static sites, and I’ve grown particularly fond of the static site generator Eleventy. The other day, I came across an article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/migrate/wordpress/&quot;&gt;migrating from WordPress to Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;. Using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/migrate/wordpress/#use-11ty-import&quot;&gt;11ty/import tool&lt;/a&gt;, I could import all my content into an Eleventy build. Now, &lt;strong&gt;ldstephens.net&lt;/strong&gt; is a static site built with Eleventy, using HTML and CSS, and deployed on Netlify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step: Today, I transferred the domain ldstephens.net from WordPress.com to Hover. I’m now completely free from WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be posting here on a regular basis going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post - I&#39;m an American software developer and the &quot;broligarchs&quot; don&#39;t speak for me</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-im-an-american-software-developer-and-the-broligarchs-dont-speak-for-me/" />
    <updated>2025-03-25T11:09:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-im-an-american-software-developer-and-the-broligarchs-dont-speak-for-me/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ratfactor.com/tech-nope&quot;&gt;Dave Gauer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just want to be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I am, a software developer in the year 2025. I look around at &amp;quot;tech&amp;quot; in the news and in culture and I don’t like what I see. Something has gone really, really wrong with the Big Tech &amp;quot;bros&amp;quot; and I cannot keep silent about it any longer. Because the broligarchs do not represent me &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.[…] If all I can accomplish here is to be understood, that’s enough. I can, after all, only speak for myself. But I have a feeling I’m not alone. I have a feeling that there are a lot of other people in the tech world who do not want to be thought of as the cold-blooded instruments of mad kings bent on destroying everything in order to remake the world as a dystopian techno-state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent read, even if you’re not a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On - Using ChatGPT for tech support</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/on-using-chatgpt-for-tech-support/" />
    <updated>2025-03-24T16:54:13Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/on-using-chatgpt-for-tech-support/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t sure how to ask for help with software, try first asking ChatGPT or another AI chatbot to help figure out what’s going wrong. It has infinite time to help, and won’t mind if the problem turned out to be a random browser plug-in that was misbehaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/03/20/151234.html?title=usingChatgptForTechSupport&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rely on ChatGPT for almost all my tech-related questions. Just the other day, I was setting up a new snippet in Alfred for the YAML front matter of a blog post. I wanted the timestamp format to be 2025-03-20T14:09:02Z, so I asked ChatGPT for the correct Alfred time and date syntax. It gave me this: &lt;code&gt;{date:yyyy-MM-dd&#39;T&#39;HH:mm:ss&#39;Z&#39;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have a snippet that instantly inserts the front matter into a document with the current date and time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ---
    title:
    description:
    date: 2025-03-20T14:09:02Z
    tags:
       - posts
    layout: layouts/post.njk
    ---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way fucking easier than sifting through Google results, hoping to find the right answer. Here are some ways I’ve recently used ChatGPT for tech support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting common software issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to do something in an app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting macOS problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running commands in Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up and maintaining my 11ty-powered website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixing hosting and deployment issues with Netlify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging HTML, CSS, and JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigating GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automating tasks with Shortcuts, AppleScript, and Automator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not using ChatGPT for tech support, give it a shot. It’s like having an expert on call minus the frustration of Googling.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>