<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://ldstephens.net/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://ldstephens.net/" />
  <updated>2025-03-27T15:55:06Z</updated>
  <id>https://ldstephens.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Loren Stephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Update regarding ldstephens - March 27, 2025</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-regarding-ldstephens-march-27-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-03-27T15:55:06Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/update-regarding-ldstephens-march-27-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, you may have noticed a flurry of activity here at ldstephens in the last few days. As long-time followers know, this site started on WordPress.com in 2016. Around the time WordPress made changes to the editor forcing users to use the new block editor that I fucking hated I basically stopped posting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past several months, I’ve been experimenting with static sites, and I’ve grown particularly fond of the static site generator Eleventy. The other day, I came across an article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/migrate/wordpress/&quot;&gt;migrating from WordPress to Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;. Using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/migrate/wordpress/#use-11ty-import&quot;&gt;11ty/import tool&lt;/a&gt;, I could import all my content into an Eleventy build. Now, &lt;strong&gt;ldstephens.net&lt;/strong&gt; is a static site built with Eleventy, using HTML and CSS, and deployed on Netlify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step: Today, I transferred the domain ldstephens.net from WordPress.com to Hover. I’m now completely free from WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be posting here on a regular basis going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post - I&#39;m an American software developer and the &quot;broligarchs&quot; don&#39;t speak for me</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-im-an-american-software-developer-and-the-broligarchs-dont-speak-for-me/" />
    <updated>2025-03-25T11:09:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/link-post-im-an-american-software-developer-and-the-broligarchs-dont-speak-for-me/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ratfactor.com/tech-nope&quot;&gt;Dave Gauer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just want to be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I am, a software developer in the year 2025. I look around at &amp;quot;tech&amp;quot; in the news and in culture and I don’t like what I see. Something has gone really, really wrong with the Big Tech &amp;quot;bros&amp;quot; and I cannot keep silent about it any longer. Because the broligarchs do not represent me &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.[…] If all I can accomplish here is to be understood, that’s enough. I can, after all, only speak for myself. But I have a feeling I’m not alone. I have a feeling that there are a lot of other people in the tech world who do not want to be thought of as the cold-blooded instruments of mad kings bent on destroying everything in order to remake the world as a dystopian techno-state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent read, even if you’re not a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On - Using ChatGPT for tech support</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/on-using-chatgpt-for-tech-support/" />
    <updated>2025-03-24T16:54:13Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/on-using-chatgpt-for-tech-support/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t sure how to ask for help with software, try first asking ChatGPT or another AI chatbot to help figure out what’s going wrong. It has infinite time to help, and won’t mind if the problem turned out to be a random browser plug-in that was misbehaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/03/20/151234.html?title=usingChatgptForTechSupport&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rely on ChatGPT for almost all my tech-related questions. Just the other day, I was setting up a new snippet in Alfred for the YAML front matter of a blog post. I wanted the timestamp format to be 2025-03-20T14:09:02Z, so I asked ChatGPT for the correct Alfred time and date syntax. It gave me this: &lt;code&gt;{date:yyyy-MM-dd&#39;T&#39;HH:mm:ss&#39;Z&#39;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have a snippet that instantly inserts the front matter into a document with the current date and time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ---
    title:
    description:
    date: 2025-03-20T14:09:02Z
    tags:
       - posts
    layout: layouts/post.njk
    ---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way fucking easier than sifting through Google results, hoping to find the right answer. Here are some ways I’ve recently used ChatGPT for tech support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting common software issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to do something in an app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting macOS problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running commands in Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up and maintaining my 11ty-powered website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixing hosting and deployment issues with Netlify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging HTML, CSS, and JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigating GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automating tasks with Shortcuts, AppleScript, and Automator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not using ChatGPT for tech support, give it a shot. It’s like having an expert on call minus the frustration of Googling.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Uses</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/uses-2025-03-24/" />
    <updated>2025-03-24T14:06:13Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/uses-2025-03-24/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Updated: March 24, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop: M1 13” Macbook Air&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peripherals:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic Mouse 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Air Pods Pro 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apps:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;macOS: 15.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail App: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Apple Notes / Drafts / Plain Text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud File Storage: iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari / Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Editor: Drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code: GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Editor: VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal: Drafts / Day One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launcher: Alfred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS Service: Feedbin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS App: Reeder Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Manager: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPN: TunnelBear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilities: Hazel, Keyboard Maestro, PopClip, Yoink, DropZone, App Cleaner, Moom, Witch, Hidden Bar, ScreenFloat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile: iPhone 15 Pro Max and M2 11” iPad Air&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peripherals:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Air Pods Pro 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apps:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iOS: 18.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail App: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messages: Messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Apple Notes / Drafts / Plain Text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text: Drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS Service: Feedbin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS App: Reeder Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal: Drafts / Day One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Manager: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather: Carrot Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health and Fitness: Fitness, FoodNoms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This makes my fucking blood boil!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/this-makes-my-fucking-blood-boil/" />
    <updated>2025-03-22T10:15:28Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/this-makes-my-fucking-blood-boil/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Emily Peck,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/21/social-security-lutnick-doge-checks&quot;&gt; writing for Axios&lt;/a&gt;: Seniors won&#39;t complain if they miss a Social Security check, Lutnick says&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commerce secretary Howard Lutnick suggested this week that only &amp;quot;fraudsters&amp;quot; would complain about missing a monthly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/20/doge-social-security-deposit-fraud&quot;&gt;Social Security&lt;/a&gt; check, and that most people wouldn&#39;t mind if the government simply skipped a payment.[…] More than 70 million Americans get a Social Security benefit every month, and for many, those checks are their only income.[…] &amp;quot;Let&#39;s say Social Security didn&#39;t send out their checks this month. My mother-in-law, who&#39;s 94, she wouldn&#39;t call and complain,&amp;quot; Lutnick — a billionaire former Wall Street CEO — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=182ckTL2KBA&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; the billionaire &amp;quot;All In&amp;quot; podcast host Chamath Palihapitiya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of shit just makes my fucking blood boil. As many of you know you know I’m 80 years old. I depend on my monthly Social Security check to live. Would I miss a check? Hell yes! So would millions of other seniors Republicans, Democrats, Independents, and those who don’t give a shit about politics. For some, it’s their &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; source of income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not like we’re getting a freebie here. We all paid into Social Security and Medicare our entire working lives. I started working when I was 15 years old and was never without a job until I retired. So I paid my fucking dues and so did all other seniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but sure, let&#39;s just skip a payment, what could possibly go wrong? Maybe Lutnick thinks we can all just hop on our yachts and ride out the month, or maybe we should start selling off our prescription meds to make rent. The sheer arrogance of a billionaire pretending he knows what it&#39;s like to rely on Social Security is bullshit. News flash: We&#39;re not asking for a favor. We&#39;re demanding what we &lt;em&gt;earned&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can tell I’m pissed. &lt;em&gt;Don’t fuck with our Social Security and Medicare!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More thoughts on the M4 MacBook Air</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/more-thoughts-on-the-m4-macbook-airs/" />
    <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/more-thoughts-on-the-m4-macbook-airs/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ben Lovejoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2025/03/21/buying-a-five-year-old-macbook-air-was-the-right-decision-for-me/&quot;&gt;wrote this on 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;, and it hit home. He said, “Having had the chance to try out the new machine in an Apple Store, I&#39;m not &lt;em&gt;100%&lt;/em&gt; sure I&#39;d favor an upgrade even if it were the same price … […] But it doesn&#39;t offer any real benefit to me[…] In fact, when I visited an Apple Store to compare the M1 and M4 models side-by-side[…] But if like me your usage will be a mix of writing, other light tasks like email and web, and perhaps a bit of photo editing, then any Apple Silicon MacBook Air is good enough. At that point, you have to figure out whether any of the M4 features are worth the price difference to you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben&#39;s experience reinforces what &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/thinking-about-the-m4-macbook-air/&quot;&gt;I wrote&lt;/a&gt; the other day. He actually went to an Apple Store and compared the M1 and M4 models side-by-side! And even after that, he wasn&#39;t convinced the upgrade was necessary for his workflow. That&#39;s exactly how I feel. I&#39;ve been using my M1 for everyday tasks, and it handles everything without breaking a sweat. If someone who&#39;s tested both models doesn&#39;t see a significant benefit, then I definitely don&#39;t need to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s tempting to get caught up in the hype of new tech, but Ben&#39;s quote is a great reminder to be realistic about my needs. Why spend extra money on something I won&#39;t even fully utilize? Ben&#39;s words have solidified my decision to stick with my M1 Air.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple ID phishing alert</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/apple-id-phishing-alert/" />
    <updated>2025-03-20T09:25:58Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/apple-id-phishing-alert/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, just a heads-up for Mac users: there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2025/03/20/this-is-one-of-the-most-sophisticated-phishing-attacks-ever-made-against-mac-users/&quot;&gt;new phishing scam&lt;/a&gt; going around. It starts with a fake security alert while you’re browsing, but this one goes a step further by freezing the page, making it seem like your Mac is locked making the scam feel more real. The goal is to trick you into entering your Apple ID and password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see one of these popups and the page is frozen, press Command + Option + Esc, select Safari, and force quit to force quit the app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Barry Hess</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/quoting-barry-hess/" />
    <updated>2025-03-16T11:31:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/quoting-barry-hess/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is a conversation. It’s a conversation with yourself and it’s a conversation with others.[…] You don’t have to be an essayist. (Though you can be one if you want!) Don’t let those essayists discourage you from blogging. Just write. Just blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bjhess.com/posts/you-re-a-blogger-not-an-essayist&quot;&gt;Barry Hess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting - 16 March 2025 11:13 AM</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/quoting-16-march-2025-1113-am/" />
    <updated>2025-03-16T11:18:11Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/quoting-16-march-2025-1113-am/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;why write? like art i write not thinking about the reader but trying to compose my thoughts into some kind of cogent experience for me and bringing the reader along as sort of a secondary consideration. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrbrianpuck.wordpress.com/2025/03/15/why-write-right/&quot;&gt;why write right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It benefits literally everyone except Apple’s shareholders if people keep their devices for years longer. Durable technology is bad business. Apple, of course, built it’s name on quality, so they can’t make their products bad. They need to be good enough for the prices they command, but not so good that you keep them too long. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gomakethings.com/durable-technology/&quot;&gt;Durable technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PSA - Amazon will log all Echo voice commands starting March 28</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.net/blog/psa-amazon-will-log-all-echo-voice-commands-starting-march-28/" />
    <updated>2025-03-15T16:38:14Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.net/blog/psa-amazon-will-log-all-echo-voice-commands-starting-march-28/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t use Alexa but if you do you might want to consider if you want to continue using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scharon Harding, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/everything-you-say-to-your-echo-will-be-sent-to-amazon-starting-on-march-28/&quot;&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an email sent to customers today, Amazon said that Echo users will no longer be able to set their devices to process Alexa requests locally and, therefore, avoid sending voice recordings to Amazon’s cloud. Amazon apparently sent the email to users with “Do Not Send Voice Recordings” enabled on their Echo. Starting on March 28, recordings of everything spoken to the Alexa living in Echo speakers and smart displays will automatically be sent to Amazon and processed in the cloud.[…] there are plenty of reasons why people wouldn&#39;t want Amazon to receive recordings of what they say to their personal device. For one, the idea of a conglomerate being able to listen to personal requests made in your home is, simply, unnerving.[…] Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201602230&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; it allows employees to listen to Alexa voice recordings to train its speech recognition and natural language understanding systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>