<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>ldstephens - notes</title>
        <link>https://ldstephens.net/notes/</link>
        <description>My notes</description>
        <atom:link
            href="https://ldstephens.net/notes-feed.xml"
            rel="self"
            type="application/rss+xml"
        />
        <image>
            <url>https://ldstephens.net/favicon.png</url>
            <title>ldstephens - notes</title>
            <link>https://ldstephens.net/notes/</link>
        </image>

        <item>
            <title>January 14, 2026, at 9:37:46 AM</title>
            <link>https://ldstephens.net/notes/</link>
            <description>
            <![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://afranca.com.br/why-people-should-not-ask-for-donations-or-money-to-run-their-own-personal-blog/">Andre Franca, Why People Should Not Ask for Donations or Money to Run Their Own Personal Blog</a></p>

            <blockquote>
            <p>Why do you run a blog? Is it to make a living, or is it a hobby? If you write from your small corner of the internet for pleasure, to meet new people, or simply for engagement, then you probably shouldn’t ask for money for it. Here&#8217;s why:</p>

            <p>[…]</p>

            <p>First, asking for donations creates an implicit transaction, even when framed as &#8220;optional&#8221;. Readers may feel entitled to certain topics, frequency, or opinions.</p>

            <p>Second, financial incentives often (if not always) influence behavior. Writers may unconsciously avoid controversial opinions, difficult topics, or experimental ideas out of fear of alienating supporters. This certainly leads to self-censorship, where authenticity is sacrificed in favor of maintaining income. There are many examples of this among content creators out there.</p>

            <p>Third, the barrier to entry for blogging has never been lower. Today, there are countless ways to build an online presence, and running a blog can cost little to nothing. When the costs of running a blog are minimal or nonexistent, requesting money becomes harder to justify, especially for a purely personal website.</p>

            <p>[…]</p>

            <p>Finally, without financial pressure, writers are free to write irregularly, change direction, or even stop altogether. At least, that is how I feel about this blog.</p>
            </blockquote>

            <p><em>For my own site</em>, I agree in principle.</p>

            <p>A personal blog, for me, is my space where I share how I&#8217;m using my tech, random thoughts, and the occasional rant. I don&#8217;t want to feel obligated to produce posts, stick to specific topics, or maintain consistency. Even optional donations can alter that dynamic, at least in my own mind.</p>

            <p>Blogging isn&#8217;t expensive anymore. A domain and basic hosting cost very little, and I&#8217;m happy to cover that expense myself.</p>

            <p>I appreciate that my blog doesn&#8217;t have to perform. It doesn&#8217;t need to grow or justify its existence. It can be valuable to a few people, or just to me.</p>

            <p>What are your thoughts?</p>
            ]]>
             </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:43:09 -0500</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
